our first solution to this problem is
that we don't do out of order load store
execution instead we do in order load
store execution this is what happens in
that case the load is a miss the ad is
stalled the store is stalled because of
that cuz they're both both waiting for
the load to eventually finish the
subtraction gets done we now know the
address for this load at that point in
the load store Q we will check whether
there are any preceding instructions
that might eventually resolve to the
same address or even worse we check
whether there is just all preceding
instructions are done because this load
is not done we're not going to consider
this store for execution that is for
producing the value for this address and
as a result we're also not going to do
this load so pretty much what now
happens is this load here doesn't go to
memory although it knows where the
address is eventually this Miss is
resolved we compute R7 and then very
quickly
afterwards we we're going to compute the
address for the store so now what we
have is this load gets done this
instruction was already done eventually
the ad gets done and eventually the
store gets done the store is considered
done not when it commits but when it
actually knows the address and knows the
value that is going to go to that
address at that point only this load is
allowed to proceed because at that point
it can just go up and check whether any
stores produce the value for the address
that we are interested in and if so just
grab the value so the load can only
finish after this store has finished and
this store will not do anything until
this load is done Etc so really we are
executing most of the instructions out
of order here but loads and stores are
still proceeding in order of course you
can see that this is suboptimal if this
store doesn't store to the same address
we have been waiting here for a very
long time and thus we have delayed all
of the destructions that depend on the
load worse if the load would have been a
cash Miss we were sitting there not
trying to order things from memory until
many many cycles later potentially and
only then we realize we have a cash Miss
and have to wait a many many cycles more
so this is of course not a very high
performance solution but it is a correct
solution